hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TOs automation playlist so
continuing with the obstacles and coming
on to the next obstacle which is on the
complex table interactions so as per
this obstacle we need to click the edit
button for John do okay and this is the
row as you can see now the complexity
behind this and why it is a hard
obstacle is because if I refresh this
page you will see that uh the row will
keep on changing so as you can see this
particular row where John do exists it
keeps on changing as I keep on
refreshing the page so there is no
guarantee that when you open the page uh
this will still be in the same row right
so it is dynamically changing and we
need to use the constraint action mode
to basically uh find out the row where
this particular uh data exists and then
uh we need to also click on the edit
button okay so this is what we need to
do so the first thing is obviously uh we
need to scan that particular table so
I'm going here and I'm going to scan the
application okay so here uh I'm going to
scan the application and then uh we are
going to use the table here and also uh
we are going to add this edit button
okay so for now it will show that the
selected item is not unique because
there are lots of different edit buttons
on the rows but don't worry about this
we will take care of this automatically
when uh we write the test case okay so
I'm going to rename this module to this
particular
obstacle okay and then I'm going to save
and I'm going to
close right uh so now coming back here
uh we have got our obstacle and then
let's go to our test cases folder here
I'm going to create a new test case and
rename it with that particular uh ID of
the obstacle and then um I'm going to
drag the module right here
so inside this you will see that we have
the table and then we have got the edit
button right now if you look back at
this module uh you will notice that this
table is not organized uh in the same
manner as it is displayed on the web
page why because every row has got these
two buttons right and we need the edit
button but uh it should be under this
particular row right or any particular
Row in the table but if you look at this
module the edit button is outside the
row or column it is inside the table
which is not correct right because uh if
I'm selecting any row then I want to
click on that particular edit button
right so we need to decide this
dynamically um and to do this what we
will do is we will uh change this
position of uh this particular element
and uh will put it from the table to a
particular row okay so what we're going
to do uh we are going to drag this edit
control and put it inside the row so
that along with the cell we have also
got the edit button okay so you can
rearrange the module attributes as you
like within the module okay so here now
if I come back and now you can see under
the table we have got the row we have
got the cell and we have got the edit
button right so the first job is to
obviously find out the the row uh which
contains that particular value right and
for that I'm going to the cell value
here and I'm going to go with the first
name uh now we know our first name is
John and I'm going to change this action
mode to
constraint okay now also you will notice
that uh John is not the unique first
name there are two rows with the same
name so we need to also put a constraint
on the last name okay so here again um I
will choose the cell as last name and
again I will put this value here and put
a constraint so using these two
constraints it will be able to find out
the row even though it is dynamically
changing on the page okay and now we
want to click on the edit button so that
should be pretty simple so we will just
use the click operation on the edit
button once it is able to find or select
this row based on these two constraints
okay so that's the logic you need to
apply
uh in order to resolve this particular
obstacle okay so now uh let's go back
here we'll change the work state to
complete it and now let's go ahead and
run this in
scratchbook so as you can see it is able
to click on the correct edit button
using the two constraint it was able to
find out the row which contains the
first name as John and last name as to
and uh it was able to complete this
obstacle so these are uh the particular
actions which you need to perform in
your test case in order to complete this
particular
obstacle that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video